transamerica.com 2019-07-30

# Privacy Policy

#### 

**Effective Date:**  September 20, 2016

This Online Privacy Statement (Statement) applies to this website or mobile application and the websites or mobile applications of Transamerica Corporation, and any of its U.S. subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively “we”, “us” or “our”) that link to this Statement (each a Site and collectively, the Sites). This Statement describes how Sites may collect, use and share information about you.

The Sites are intended for a U.S. audience. If you access one of our Sites from outside the United States, your information may be transferred or processed in the United States.

Depending on how you interact with us, and which of our affiliates provide the products and services you chose, your policy or contract and additional Transamerica and Transamerica affiliate privacy practices may also be applicable.

Information We Collect Online| Children's Privacy Rights  
---|---  
How We May Use the Information We Collect| Accessing Your Data  
Social Media| Protecting Your Data  
Advertising Networks| Disputes  
Information We Share| Updates to this Privacy Statement  
Your Choices| How to Contact Us  

 **Information We Collect Online**

 **Information You Provide.** We collect information that you provide to us at the Sites, through applications, online forms and calculators, surveys and other communications. For example, we collect your information at the Sites when you:

  * make information available to us via social networking logins, such as Facebook or Twitter;
  * participate in chats, web forums or other interactive sessions;
  * subscribe to newsletters or provide feedback;
  * participate in surveys, sweepstakes or other promotions;
  * conduct searches through the Site;
  * purchase or request a quote for an insurance product or other service;
  * use Site tools and resources that request your or your family’s information;
  * use our e-Billing services or manage your account and investment options through the Site;
  * access other applications and services from this site, such as applying for a job or using the Locate an Agent function;
  * register for or manage a policy, contract or account; or
  * request additional information.

This information may include name, address, telephone number, email address, date of birth, policy, contract or account numbers and, where reasonably required to complete the request or transaction, banking information, credit card number, Social Security number, driver’s license numbers and other information.

 **Usage Metrics.** Information regarding your use of this Site may be collected and/or aggregated through the use of automated means. This information may include:

  * your IP address, and the type of browser and operating system used;
  * date and time you access the Site and the pages you visit, and, if you linked from or to another website, the address of that website;
  * email you open and links you click on within those emails;
  * the duration of your use and the features and content you access; and
  * information regarding your ISP or mobile carrier, and the type of handheld or mobile device that you used.

 **Data Technologies.** Various technologies may be used to automatically collect information on the Site, such as cookies, web beacons and local shared objects. “Cookies” are small identifiers sent from a web server that are stored on your device for the purpose of identifying your browser or storing information or settings in your browser. A “web beacon,” also known as an Internet tag, pixel tag or clear GIF, connects web pages to web servers and their cookies. “Local shared objects,” sometimes known as Flash cookies, may be used to personalize your visit by storing your preferences or displaying content based upon what you have viewed on various websites. Anonymous advertising identifiers may be used on mobile devices and otherwise in a manner similar to cookies. We refer to these types of technologies generally as “Data Technologies,” which include today’s technologies and similar types of technologies as they evolve over time.

One or more Data Technologies may be used by us on this Site and other websites and mobile applications (including websites that may not be operated by Transamerica). Third parties, who may have their own privacy policies, may also use Data Technologies to collect information on this or other websites.

When you download or use apps or mobile-optimized websites to access our site or online services (“Mobile Sites”), we may receive information about your location and your mobile device, including a unique identifier for your device, device settings, analytical information about how you use your mobile device, and other information that may be stored on or accessed through your mobile device, including from apps not operated by Transamerica or from other devices connected to your mobile device. This information helps us provide you with location-based services, advertising, search results, and other personalized content. Most mobile devices allow you to turn off location services by accessing the device’s settings menu.

 **Publicly Posted Information.** Information that you make available to us and others via social media networks, forums, blogs, listserves, chat rooms or similar functionality is information that we or others may share or use in accordance with the law.

 **Information from Other Sources.** We may also collect information about you from third party sources, including from commercially available third-party sources, such as credit reporting agencies or other companies that collect or analyze information about consumers or users. Examples of information we receive from other sources includes credit history information from credit bureaus, which we use to help prevent and detect fraud and to offer certain credit or financial services to some customers.

 **Combined Information.** We may combine the information you provide us with the other information that we collect about you.

 **How We May Use the Information We Collect**

 **We may use information we collect for a variety of purposes, including the following:**

  * for our everyday business purposes, such as establishing and administering your policy, contract or account, providing information you request and providing customer support;
  * to evaluate your eligibility for such products or services;
  * to provide you with up to date information regarding the Site, your policies, contracts or accounts, including changes to terms and conditions and/or other administrative information;
  * for special events, programs, surveys, contests, sweepstakes and other offers or promotions, some of which may have additional rules or provisions addressing how your personal information is used or shared;
  * to develop new products and services and analyze the effectiveness of products, services, applications and websites;
  * to deliver marketing communications that we think may interest you, including, ads or offers tailored to you;
  * to deliver content (including advertising) correlating to your interests and browsing and usage history, both within this Site and on other websites and applications;
  * to provide retirement calculators, assessments, and other financial planning tools on the Sites;
  * to comply with the law and legal advice;
  * to prevent fraud and enhance security;
  * to allow you to utilize features within our Sites by granting us access to information from your device such as contact lists, or geolocation when you request certain services;
  * to provide you with location-based services, advertising, search results, and other personalized content;
  * to contact you via telephone, text or chat; and
  * for other purposes permitted by law or to which you consent.

We may also use data that we collect on an aggregate or anonymous basis (such that it does not identify any individual visitor) for various business purposes, where permissible under applicable laws and regulations.

#### 

Privacy Policy PDF
